Siddaharth Suman

Software Engineer III

Objectives

Looking for a continuous learning environment and professional growth in an organization where my skills are adequately utilized.

I wish to contribute the skills that I have learned over the years for the betterment of the organization.

About Me

I am a Software Engineer III with a total experience of 4 years working with FactSet Systems India Pvt Ltd.

I am a self-motivated and adaptable kind of individual who yearns to get his hands on the latest trends in technology.

I am a quick learner and a team player who is neither afraid to take lead nor afraid to ask for help in case I get stuck anywhere. I possess good communication, interpersonal, and leadership skills and can effectively deal with teammates and clients. I am always willing to help others in need and motivate them and boost their morale.

I like to work as a team and look forward to working with teams where I can contribute with my expertise as well as learn from.

Experience

Dec 2018 -Present Software Engineer III

FactSet Systems India Pvt. Ltd.

Dec 2015 - Dec 2018 Senior System Engineer

· Worked on web applications and mobile applications

· Worked on development of automated tools and perform testing of web applications

· Provided middleware support

Aug 2015 - Oct 2015 Assistant Professor

Institute of Forensic Science

· Worked as a faculty for the institute

• Taught the subject of Cyber Forensics and Offenses

May 2014 - Oct 2014 Freelancer

Infosys Ltd.

Palmate Solutions

Worked as a Backend Web Developer

Jan 2014 - Mar 2014 Intern

TechMeet

Worked as an Android Application Developer

Jun 2013 - Oct 2013 Intern

Opine Solutions

Worked as an Android Application Developer

Projects

Partner Assessment Portal Technologies: Angular 5, Bulma, CSS, HTML, Javascript, Typescript

Team Size: 8

 Portal for partners of the firm to be assessed on their performance and get recommendation for salary changes

· Superiors can see a partner's summary, history and other information

• Superiors can provide a salary recommendation for partners based on their assessment

· Worked directly with client

Profile and Rewards Web Application **Technologies:** Angular 4, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, jQuery, Javascript, Typescript **Team Size:** 12

• Employee centric dashboard with various reports and details of the employee

• Employees can generate their compensation, health and time off related reports

Received appreciation from teammates and onsite team as well for good performance

Geofence and Custom Plugin for Workspace Reservation Technologies: Android, Ionic, Cordova

Team Size: 10

· Application for employees for reserving workspaces in their office

• Employees can reserve workspaces on a temporary or regular basis as well

 Employees can schedule reservation for future dates and can automatically get a reservation as soon as entering the work area

MobileIron Downloads Report Tool **Technologies:** Selenium, JavaFX, Apache POI, MobileIron, Microsoft Excel, PhantomJS **Team Size:** 1

Automation tool that generates reports for 80+ production applications

• Enables employees to work on other tasks and not be blocked on creating report manually

• Manual report generation blocks an employee for 1 hour and is prone to human errors

The tool takes under 5 minutes to generate the report and is accurate every time

• Received appreciation from offshore as well as onshore team for simplicity and time saving

Personal Info

Phone

+91 9920760964

E-mail

siddaharthsuman@gmail.com

Date of birth

December 18, 1993

Marital Status

Unmarried

Github

github.com/SiddaharthSuman

Frontend Technologies/ Frameworks

Angular

Vue.js

Bulma

Bootstrap

Java Swing

JavaFX

Backend Technologies/ Frameworks

• Node.js

• Php

Servlets

Mobile Technologies

• Android

Markup and Scripting Languages

• HTML

JavaScript

• CSS

jQuery

• Php

Programming Languages

Java

Typescript

• C++

• Python

Testing Frameworks and Tools

• Selenium

· Katalon Studio

Coded UI

HP UFT

Databases

MySQL

MSSQL

• MongoDB

Version Control

Bitbucket

GitTools

TeamCity

HP Application

 HP Service Manager 9 Lifecycle Management

 Visual Studio TFS IBM Websphere

IDEs and Editors

Eclipse

 Visual Studio Code

AtomSublime Text

Android Studio

Operating Systems

• Windows

Mac OS

• Linux

PwC Application Details Portal	Technologies: Angular 4, Php, Servlets, Google Drive, Soap Team Size: 1 Portal for details of applications supported by the support team Gives access to internal details of 26+ applications across many territories Facility to manage applications list, ping application's soap services and manage relevant documents using integrated Google Drive support Performs automatic healthcheck for all the applications Received appreciation from team
Infosys Buy/Sell App for Android	Technologies: Android, Php, MySQL Team Size: 5 App for a buy/sell platform Users can post items for selling and can also see other posts Users can show interest in an item for sale and contact the seller
Education	
Sep 2011 - May 2015	 Atharva College of Engineering, Mumbai University, BE in Computer Engineering, 2015 Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" for EXTC faculties Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" for CMPN and INFT faculties Conducted Training and Placement Session on "C++" for final year students Held the posts of Assistant Technical Head and Technical Head for Computer Society of India, Atharva Speaker for workshop on "Java Primer" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva Speaker for workshop on "Backend Web Development" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva

Languages

EnglishMarathi

• Hindi

Organised Google Dev Fest for Google Developer's Group till Mar 2011 Kendriya Vidyalaya INS Hamla, Mumbai

Publications

Feb 2015 Supercharging web applications with Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-1 Feb 2015)

Jun 2015 Information system using Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-3 June 2015)